

Taeyoung Kim

ROBOTICS · PERCEPTION ENGINEER

340, Mokdongseo-ro, Yangcheon-gu, Seoul, 08089, Republic of Korea

□ (+82) 10-9686-8177 | ■ tyoung96@naver.com | ★ taeyoung96.github.io | □ Taeyoung96

"Nothing ventured, nothing gained."

Summary

This is Taeyoung Kim, who wants to become an autonomous driving or robotics Perception engineer. My research interests are Computer Vision and SLAM. I like to take on challenging tasks and I like to grow up with my colleagues around me. That's why I record and share what I did on my Github or Technical Blog. I'm also interested in contributing open-source projects.

Research Interests

Computer Vision Object Detection, Segmentation, Depth Estimation, 3D reconstruction

SLAM Visual SLAM, Visual Odometry

Education _____

Kwang Woon University

Seoul, S.Korea

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2022 (Expected)

B.S. IN SCHOOL OF ROBOTICS

• Current GPA: 4.09 / 4.50, Current Major GPA: 4.40 / 4.50

• Club: BARAM (Robotics Academic Group) - [2020 Staff], DAISY (English Conversation Club) - [2019 Spring President]

Work Experience

Computer Vision Lab @Korea Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

UNDERGRADUATE LAB INTERN (ADVISOR: PROF. SANGPIL KIM)

Mar. 2021 - Jul. 2021

- Research on Computer Vision using an Event camera
- Event data processing using ESIM

KIST(Korea Institute of Science and Technology)

Seoul, S.Korea

STUDENT INTERN (ADVISOR : Dr. KANGGEON KIM)

Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Research on Monocular Depth Estimation
- Participated in KIST disinfect robot (AI Disinfection Robot) project [Video]

Image Process System Lab @Kwang Woon Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

Undergraduate Lab Intern (Advisor: Prof. Donggyu Sim)

May. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Research on Image Processing based on Deep learning
- Participated in seminars related to Deep Learning and Image Processing

Skills

Programming C++ / C, Python, JAVA, Matlab
Framework Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras
DevOps Git, Docker, ROS2 / ROS
Languages Korean, English

Publication

INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL

Special Issues: Digital Healthcare in Pandemics, Heeju Hong, Wonkook Shin, Jieun Oh, Sunwoo Lee, Taeyoung Kim, Woosub Lee, Jongsuk Choi, Seungbeum Suh and Kanggeon Kim,

2021.11 "Standard for the Quantification of a Sterilization Effect Using an Artificial Intelligence Disinfection Robot" -

[Paper], [Link]

Sensors

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE

2021.7	UR2021 (Work in progress) , Taeyoung Kim, Omer Faruk Ince, JongBeom Baek, Jun-Sik Kim, KangGeon Kim,	
	"Dense Monocular SLAM applied Depth Estimation" - [Paper], [Video]	KROS

DOMESTIC CONFERENCE

2021.5	KROS2021, TaeHwan Kim, Taeyoung Kim, GiJae Lee, KangGeon Kim, "Recognition of disinfection targets and generation of semantic map for disinfection robot" - [Paper]	KROS
2020.9	KSPC2020 , Naseong Kwon, Taeyoung Kim, Subin Kim, Joohyung Byeon, Jongsuk Lee, Donggyu Sim, "Luma Mapping with Chroma Scaling based on CNN feature map for VVC subjective quality improvement" - [Paper]	IEIE

Honors & Awards

AWARDS

2020.11 Dean's List , for Academic Excellence	KwangWoon Univ.
2020.9 5th Place on B-track . Korea Health Datathon 2020	NAVER CLOUD
2020.9 Still Place on B-track, Norea Health Dalathon 2020	PLATFORM
2019.10 Dean's List , for Academic Excellence	KwanaWoon Univ.

HONORS

National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship ,	Korea Student Aid
for the students, those who have been recommended by the university (Full tuition Scholarship)	Foundation
National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship ,	Korea Student Aid
for the students, those who have been recommended by the university (Full tuition Scholarship)	Foundation
Full tuition Scholarship, for Top seat last semester	KwangWoon Univ.
	for the students, those who have been recommended by the university (Full tuition Scholarship) National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship ,

Extracurricular Activity

Technical Blogs Github blog

WRITERS May. 2020 - Present

- You can easily access the blog using [this link].
- · Writing some posts about lecture summary, paper review, some tips for developments.
- To share what I have studied with others and to remember it longer.

2021 Open Source Contribution Academy

MENTEE Aug. 2021 - Nov. 2021

- I am in the process of translating a Pytorch tutorial into Korean that I want to contribute to the spread of PyTorch.
- Using Github, I developed the ability to collaborate and contribute to open source.
- The open source repository I've contributed can be found [here].

CLOVA AI RUSH 2021 NAVER AI Lab, NAVER CLOVA

May. 2021 - Jun.2021

- Only 150 students are allowed to participate in this project.
- I developed my own deep learning model related to multi-label classification.
- I ranked 30th on Project 1-3.

PERSONAL TOY PROJECT

2021 Spring Capstone Design

KwangWoon Univ. Mar. 2021 - Jun.2021

• I made a wireless charging electric vehicle charging robot.

- · I designed the control input algorithm, trained deep learning model, and developed the ROS package.
- The source code related to this project is on my [Github repository].

Monocular Depth Estimation with ORB-SLAM2

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

Sep. 2020 - Nov. 2020

Ministry of Science and ICT

• I was curious about the performance of the recent depth estimation model.

- Tused 'Monocular Depth Estimation with Transfer Learning pretrained MobileNetV2' model and applied to ORB-SLAM2 also compared with ORB-SLAM2(Monocular mode), ORB-SLAM2(RGB-D mode)
- The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].

TAEYOUNG KIM · CURRICULUM VITAE NOVEMBER 24, 2021

Runner Alarm System based on Deep Learning

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

PERSONAL TOY PROJECT Apr. 2020 - Jun. 2020

- I wanted to distinguish between walking children and running children with an object detection model.
- When children are running for an amount of time, a beep sounds.
 The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].